Fallout New Vegas is the sequel to the first Fallout
game, that for some reason has a three at the end.
But is it better?
- Is a debate we are going to stay FAR away from, because people get violent.
New Vegas was developed by Obsidian, and not
Bethesda, but that Bethesda feel is still there.
*crashes*
Seriously, the official Bethesda motto is "Bug testing is for loserz."
Now, I'm being a bit unfair;
Obsidian were asked to develop the entire game in an afternoon.
Another interesting thing is that while the game calls itself New Vegas,
much like real life, there is fuck all to do in the actual Vegas,
so the game mostly takes place in Paradise
and in the Mojave desert.
Sadly, they immediately rejected the first official name,
Fallout: Mostly Nearby New Vegas.
The game starts with a CGI intro that shows Vegas
and a bunch of exposition.
But the important thing is that you are a courier
and you couldn't make a delivery because
you were kidnapped by this ugly 3D model.
And something tells me he is NOT
a dissatisfied customer.
Then this claymation figure shoots you.
Our hero wakes up in this guy's place.
"Well, would you look at that, I bet this is your fifth playthrough
and you really want to skip this."
"Well, that's not gonna happen."
First we get to decide our name.
Courier... That's not a real name.
There we go!
You get to pick stats; I put ONE in intelligence.
I will not need it in-game,
because I'm very intelligent in real life.
Apparently we were delivering a platinum casino chip,
and this guy took it.
Now, we ARE just a delivery man, so we should just hide
and keep our head down, but nope,
we are going full Kill Bill.
So, we are off to search for them in the city of Primm.
The game has like 70 factions that you can
become accepted or vilified with.
But there are four major factions.
Outside Primm you will find the first one,
New California Republic. The NCR is another recreation
of the United States, a democratic republic.
But this time, without any of the cool shit.
The city of Primm has been taken over by convicts,
and apparently trained soldiers can't take out
six pickpocketers mostly armed with tire irons.
Seriously, if you managed to get caught and taken to
prison in the Fallout universe,
you... are not very dangerous.
And by the way, the real United States would turn that
entire building into rubble, and for no reason,
that one too.
So you take out the prisoners with a Very Sharp Knife
Then you pickpocket a note from a guy
that says, "Travel to the city Novac through Nipton."
You travel through Nipton, a town completely destroyed
and it's inhabitants crucified.
This might look cruel, but they actually WANTED this.
All that radiation created some very weird fetishes.
Then you meet another major faction
Caesar's (Seesers) - uh, Caesar's (Kaisars) Legion.
"Tell the NCR what we did here. I'd would do it myself,
but they blocked me on Twitter. Some people just can't
handle constructive criticism.
What's important to know about the Legion is that
they are 14 year olds.
This is Novac, and in the dinosaur's mouth, a man named Manny knows the people that took you.
But he wants you to exterminate some other
people because Manny is a human supremacist.
But you don't have to, because you can just pickpocket
the information from him. Seriously, you can complete
every challenge just by pickpocketing. If only
real life were this simple. Overpopulation,
climate change, lack of drinking water. We need to solve this.
"YO BANKEY! Found this cassette in your pocket!
Solves EVERYTHING! Now it's friday,
are we gonna do this?
You have to go to Boulder City to meet up with the
guys that helped the man in the checkered suit.
They are in a Mexican Standoff with
a couple of NCR soldiers.
I was going to negotiate with them, but they attacked
me for no reason. Pretty much New Vegas summed up,
you misclick and punch a guy, and then you fail
seventeen quests. So I killed them all with
A Very Sharp Knife. Fortunately, the leader
had a paper that told me exactly who the shooter was.
And his entire biography.
This is why you put every point in luck.
Welcome to the strip! Before you can go anywhere
you have to speak with the third major faction.
Mr. House and his robots.
Hello delivery man. I want to ask you a question;
Is a man not entitled to a Platinum Chip?
No, says the m-
I mean, I mean, do you have my Platinum Chip?
Okay, no. Then go get my Platinum Chip!
Then join me; The NCR is garbage, and
the Legion should stick to Xbox Live.
Benny, the man who shot you is the CEO of Tops Casino.
There are 3 casinos on the strip:
The Ultra Luxe, the luxury casino,
Gomorrah, which as the name would imply,
is a Christian casino! All profits go to charity!
And of course, the Tops, which is a normal casino,
and probably the only one turning a profit,
because what kind of idiot would niche themselves in a post-apocalypse?!?
There is Benny, standing there clueless of his upcoming-
turns out his personality made me like him.
So I have decided to forgive Benny.
But you don't fuck the Delivery Man,
the Delivery Man fucks YOU!
So I killed and cannibalized his best friend,
thus making me his best friend!
And then he ran away! With the Platinum Chip.
How rude!
Sidenote: My character in-game is a cannibal,
but i'm not a cannibal in real life.
The Legion guy from earlier tells you that Caesar has captured Benny.
"This guy was carrying a Platinum Chip that opens
a hole behind me. Could ya go down there, and destroy anything you find?"
"Or you know, don't. I'm too lazy to check if you do anything."
Here's the last chance to decide what major faction
we want to side with and what ending we will get.
I had problems choosing. I can't pick the NCR because
they are completely worthless.
Not gonna side with Dr. House, because
I don't want to anger two great powers for a guy that controls a square kilometer.
The Legion would be cool, but i'm afraid they
might go through a goth phase or something.
The last faction, taking over New Vegas as
an independent candidate is just too much pressure.
I think controlling one companion is stressful.
Literally stressful, companions are absolute morons.
But first, we are going to decide how Benny dies.
I picked death by mad cows.
Oh, come on.
The factions questlines overlap. First they all want
you to recruit the Boomers, a group of gun crazy
people with rocket launchers, to ally with them.
To finish this mission, you can spend an hour helping out, build a relationship and learn their ways, OR
you can shoot an old nice lady in the
face
Don't judge me, I'm a very busy man!
The second faction mission is to gain
control of the strip. gain alliances with
the casinos and kill house for the
luxury casino alliance you can get rid
of those annoying companions by serving
them as a nice dinner and for Gomorrah
you can kill some Italian Americans you
think you have memories what's the
really a platinum ship no don't don't go
there pay no attention to the man in the
pod the third mission is to destroy the
local Brotherhood of sail they all want
you to exterminate the Brotherhood I'm
thinking lead writer was playing Fallout
3 and then the
goddamn robot got stuck a fourth time
and he was like that's it they have to
die in the fourth mission the President
on the NCR comes to visit three of the
factions wants to protect the president
the head of security will tell you two
quick say watch how the president dies
then reload but religion you have to
find a good hiding spot to assassinate
the president but who needs a good
hiding spot when you have a very sharp
knife
now finally here comes the final mission
the battle at hoover dam house faction
and the independent factions pretty much
have the same mission press two buttons
then throw the general of the dam for
the NCR you have to fight irate legions
camp and paste alleged then you die and
the NCR is defeated no surprise there
for the legion you have to fight your
way to the general then there's an
elaborate post fight can't help to think
that if the general had spent less time
organizing this and focus on the battle
he wouldn't be in this position after
you do this the game ends so what
faction did i pick none of them I killed
house I killed Caesar I kill the
president and the NCR ambassador I
killed my campaign manager then I
started a new faction the children's
television treat broccoli unfair faction
then we took Hoover Dam and so the
delivery man you used console sheiks to
get through the game cheated again and
the Mojave wasteland was forever changed
with no real plan the CT tbu faction
gave hoover dam to the NCR if they admit
that broccoli was actually pretty great
but the battle hurt and CR making them
even more useless than before haha just
kidding like that's even possible we
seize her dead legion drifted apart not
that we care I was only going to be a
part of the Legion until my band gets
discovered the fastest darlings got
demolished and we are probably going to
see a mission in Fallout 4 where we have
to kill some NCR troops with every other
power defeated the delivery man lay the
foundation for the new vakyam empire a
human supremacists super power with a
funny dinosaur fly the NCR soldiers are
still standing outside prim waiting
because corpses might fight back or
something this slide keeps coming up
every time I finish the game I have no
idea who any of these people are and so
another game in the series ends with a
slide show because it's Fallout and
fallout never changes wait no that's not
right they are all very different but it
makes sense when you think about it
and that is the kilian experience. Like
and Subscribe, Yay! Or don't, come on man. I
have no idea what to do next.
Anyone got any suggestions?
You know in my last video I pretty much said that
there is no private place to pee because
of the nuclear apocalypse, but this, this
is getting ridiculous why would anyone
want to use nukes when they see this?